middlebury.edu 2005-12-31

# Privacy Notice

## Middlebury College Online Privacy Notice

_Last updated:  September 03, 2004_

Middlebury College respects your privacy and understands that you care how information about you is used and shared. We appreciate your trust that we will do so carefully and sensibly. This notice describes our online privacy policy. By visiting Middlebury College's Web sites, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Notice.

#### What Personal Information About Visitors Does Middlebury College Gather?

The information we learn from visitors helps us personalize and continually improve your web experience at Middlebury College's Web sites. Here are the types of information we gather.   

* Information You Give Us: We receive and store any information you enter on our Web sites or give us in any other way. Click here to see examples of what we collect. You can choose not to provide certain information, but then you might not be able to take advantage of many of our features. We use the information that you provide for such purposes as responding to your requests, customizing your online experience, improving our online store, and communicating with you. 
* Automatic Information: We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us. For example, like many Web sites, we use "cookies," and we obtain certain types of information when your Web browser accesses Middlebury College's Web sites. Click here to see examples of the information we receive. A number of companies offer utilities designed to help you visit Web sites anonymously. Although we will not be able to provide you with a personalized experience at Middlebury College's Web sites if we cannot recognize you, we want you to be aware that these tools exist. 

**What About Cookies?**  

* Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser to enable our systems to recognize your browser and to provide features such as access to restricted content. 
* The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. However, cookies allow you to take full advantage of some of Middlebury.edu's coolest features, and we recommend that you leave them turned on. 

**Does Middlebury College Share The Information It Receives?**

Information about our visitors is private. We share information only as described below.

* Protection of Middlebury College and Others: We release account and other personal information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law; enforce or apply our privacy policy; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Middlebury College, our users, or others. This may include exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. Obviously, however, this does not include selling, renting, sharing, or otherwise disclosing personally identifiable information from customers for commercial purposes in violation of the commitments set forth in this Privacy Notice. 
* In the case of our online store, in order to process your order, we need to authorize your credit card. This information is transmitted securely in encrypted format to the authorizer. In addition, when we ship your order, your name and shipping address will appear on the package. 

**How Secure Is Information About Me?**  

* We work to protect the security of your information during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information you input during transit. 
* It is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when finished using a shared computer. 

**Which Information Can I Access?**

Middlebury College publishes general Web Statistics which are available for viewing by anyone on-campus. Middlebury College's Online Store gives you access to a broad range of information about your store account and your interactions with us for the limited purpose of viewing and, in certain cases, updating that information. 

**Conditions of Use, Notices, and Revisions**

If you choose to visit Middlebury College's Web sites, your visit and any dispute over privacy is subject to this Privacy Notice. If you have any concern about privacy at Middlebury College's Web sites, please send us a thorough description to [webmaster@middlebury.edu](mailto:webmaster@middlebury.edu), and we will try to resolve it. The Web changes constantly, and our Privacy Notice may change also. We may e-mail periodic reminders of our Privacy Notice, unless you have instructed us not to, but you should check our Web site frequently to see recent changes. Unless stated otherwise, our current Privacy Notice applies to all information that we have about you and your account. 

**Information You Give Us**

You provide most such information when you search, interact, purchase, or communicate via a web form. For example, you provide information when you search for content; place an order through Middlebury College's Online Store; provide information in Your Account (and you might have more than one if you have used more than one e-mail address when shopping with us); communicate with us by phone, e-mail, or otherwise; and/or provide and rate Reviews.

**Automatic Information**

Examples of the information we collect and analyze include the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet; login; e-mail address; password; computer and connection information such as browser type and version, operating system, and platform; purchase history, which we sometimes aggregate with similar information from other customers to create features such as Top Sellers; the full Uniform Resource Locator (URL) clickstream to, through, and from Middlebury College's Online Store, including date and time; cookie number; phrases you searched for; and pages you visited. During some visits we may use software tools such as JavaScript to measure and collect session information, including page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page.

**Information You Can Access**

Examples of information you can access easily at Middlebury College's Web sites include general Web Statistics.  Examples of information you can access easily at Middlebury College's Online Store include up-to-date account information regarding recent store orders; personally identifiable information (including name, e-mail, password, communications preferences, e-mail notification settings and recommendations (including recent product view history, prior order history, and Favorites).
